# Daniel J. Lewis

https://daniellewis.tech • dlewisd11@gmail.com • 703-434-2110

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a passionate and versatile technology professional with a consulting background and proven ability to engage with customers in all phases of the software development lifecycle. My experience covers a broad range of roles including software engineering, development, integration, support, service delivery, project management and customer success which allows me to provide both strategic leadership and technical expertise. I am a persistent problem solver with an insatiable appetite for learning, and I am always working to expand my technical skillset. In addition, I have a strong personal interest in aviation including solo flight experience.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Deltek

#### Principal Technical Support Engineer and Delivery Leader

March 2019 - Present

- Serve on the leadership team of a global software support service delivery function
- Support customers using ERP software solutions on-premises or as-a-service in collaboration with product engineering, site reliability engineering (SRE), consulting services and customer success teams
- Troubleshoot and resolve complex software system issues relating to application, customization, integration, automation, database, network, and infrastructure layers
- Coach junior engineers on technical troubleshooting, customer support service quality, cross-functional collaboration, incident, and escalation management
- Identify, plan, and contribute to operational process improvement projects focused on customer support experience
- Manage executive-level, cross-organization customer escalations and get-to-green plans

#### Deltek

#### **Principal Extensions Development Engineer**

August 2011 - March 2019

- Developed customizations, automations and integrations relating to ERP software systems, using agile processes and various tools, technologies (Java, SQL, XML, MScript, Eclipse IDE, Postman, REST, SOAP, Git, etc.)
- · Engaged with customers as part of an agile team to gather requirements, design, build and document technical solutions
- Managed git repositories and lead development and deployment strategies for teams of multiple developers
- Performed various maintenance tasks on mission critical server systems and environments (Windows and Linux) running Deltek software including application configuration, database administration (Oracle and SQL Server), automation, etc.
- Delivered customer-facing and internal training sessions relating to software development

## **EDUCATION**

Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University Blacksburg, Virginia

Master of Information Technology Software Development Certificate Cybersecurity Technology Certificate May 2022

George Mason University Fairfax, Virginia

B.S. Information Technology Information Security Concentration Business Minor August 2011

## **CERTIFICATIONS / ACHIEVEMENTS**

Deltek CARES Leadership Development ProgramMarch 2022Deltek President's Club2017

Student Private Pilot (Airplane Single-Engine Land, ASEL) 60 Hours, Total Time

George Mason University Aviation Club (Member)

2011

George Mason University Crew/Rowing Club (President and Athlete) 2007 – 2011

Key tools and technologies include but are not limited to: Java, Python, Vue.js, Spring, RDBMS (MSSQL, Oracle, MySQL), GitHub, REST Web Services, XML, HTML, CSS, Postman, Windows, Linux, Splunk, JIRA, Eclipse IDE, VS Code, IntelliJ, AWS